A Finding Aid to the Walter Pach Papers, 1857-1980, in the Archives of American Art AAA.pachwalt2
Archives of American Art
- Selections from Walter Pach's Library, 1880-1963; Series 10; 12 Linear feet Box 11-22
  - Selected Publications, 1880-1963; 10.3
    - Montross Gallery. Henri Matisse Exhibition. New York, 1915 January 20-February 27 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Mumford, Lewis. Man as Interpreter. New York: Harcourt, Brace and Company, 1950 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Mumford, Lewis. Technics and Civilization. New York: Harcourt, Brace and Company, 1934 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Museum of Modern Art. Art in Our Time. Exhibition to celebrate the tenth anniversary of the Museum and the opening of its new building. New York. Pach lent a Duchamp painting., 1939 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Palais des Beaux-Arts. Collection de Monsieur L.L.: Tableaux modernes, Faïences de Delft et de Rhodes, Objets d'art. Brussels, 1931 December 22-23 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Parke-Bernet Galleries, Inc. Auction/Sales Catalogue. New York, October 17. Dates written in:, 1940-1941 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Parke-Bernet Galleries, Inc. Auction/Sales Catalogue. New York:, 1942 January 8 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Parke-Bernet Galleries, Inc. Classical and Medieval Stone Sculptures, Joseph Brummer Collection, Part III (Final). New York, 1949 June 8-9 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Parke-Bernet Galleries, Inc. Modern French and American Paintings from the Walter Pach, Mrs. Jacob H. Rand, and Other Collections. New York, 1949 January 6 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Parke-Bernet Galleries, Inc. Part Two of the Notable Art Collection... Joseph Brummer. New York, 1949 May 11-14 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Perkins, Christopher. On Museums: An Essay. Saint-Tropez, France: Au Paysage du Midi, 1925 (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Popular Stories Collected by the Brothers Grimm. London: Oxford University Press, 1915 (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Portraits d'hier, Studies of the Life, Works, and Influence of the Late Great Figures (Grands Morts) of Our Time 2, no. 28, 1910, May (Box 21, Folder 13)
      Includes "Paul Cézanne," by Elie Faure.
    - Raynal, Maurice. Jacques Lipchitz. Paris: Editions Jeanne Bucher, undated (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - Reality: A Journal of Artists' Opinions (New York) 1, no. 1, 1953 Spring (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - Rewald, John. Georges Seurat. New York: Wittenborn and Company, 1943 (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - Rewald, John, Dore Ashton, Harold Joachim, and Odilon Redon. Odilon Redon/Gustave Moreau/Rodolphe Bresdin. New York: Museum of Modern Art in collaboration with the Art Institute of Chicago, distributed by Doubleday & Co., Inc., 1961 (Box 21, Folder 17)
    - Rich, Daniel Catton. The Challenge of Art in the Americas: An Address Given to the Graduating Classes School of the Art Institute. Chicago, 1944 June 9 (Box 21, Folder 18)
    - Richter, J.P. Lectures on the National Gallery. London, New York, and Bombay: Longmans, Green, and Co., 1898 (Box 21, Folder 19)
    - Ritchie, Andrew Carnduff. Abstract Painting and Sculpture in America. New York: Museum of Modern Art, 1951. (Box 21, Folder 20)
      Walter Pach's painting was included in exhibition.
    - Ritchie, Andrew Carnduff. "The Evolution of Ingres' Portrait of the Comtesse d'Haussonville." Art Bulletin (College Art Association of America) 22, no. 3, Reprint, 1940 September (Box 21, Folder 21)
    - Robin, Maurice. "Eugène Delacroix," Portraits d'Hier, undated (Box 21, Folder 22)
    - Sérusier, Paul. ABC de la peinture, and ABC de la peinture: Correspondance. Paris: Henri Floury, La Douce France, 1921; (Two copies) (Box 21, Folder 23)
    - Seven Famous Greek Plays. Introduction by Whitney J. Oates and Eugene O'Neill, Jr. New York: Random House, Inc., Modern Library College Editions, 1950 (Box 21, Folder 24)
    - Severini, Gino. Ragionamenti sulle arti figurative. Milan: Editore Ulrico Hoepli, 1936 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - S.F. Bay Exposition Co. Art. Official Catalog, Golden Gate International Exposition, Palace of Fine Arts. San Francisco, 1940. (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Sloan, John, and Oliver LaFarge. Introduction to American Indian Art. New York: Exposition of Indian Tribal Arts, Inc., 1931 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Smith College Museum of Art, Tryon Art Gallery. Géricault. Northampton, Mass., 1929 April 4-25 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Société des artistes indépendants. Catalog of the 24th Exposition. Paris, 1908 March 20-May 2 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Society of Independent Artists, Inc. The Bylaws (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Society of Independent Artists, Inc. The 20th Annual Anniversary Exhibition. New York, 1936 April 24-May 17. (Box 22, Folder 7)
      Walter and Magda Pach were directors and lenders.
    - Stein, Leo. The A-B-C of Aesthetics. New York: Boni & Liveright, 1927 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Stein, Leo. Journey into the Self: Being the Letters, Papers & Journals of Leo Stein. Edited by Edmund Fuller. Introduction by Van Wyck Brooks. New York: Crown Publishers, 1950 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Taylor, Francis Henry. Babel's Tower: The Dilemma of the Modern Museum. New York: Columbia University Press, 1945 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Transition: A Quarterly Review (New York), no. 26, 1937 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Tzara, Tristan. La Première aventure céleste de Mr. Antipyrine. With color woodcuts by Marcel Janco. Zurich: Collection Dada, 1916 (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Universidad Nacional Autonoma de Mexico. Anales del Instituto de Investigaciones Esteticas. Indices to Vol. 2, nos. 5,6,7, and 8. Mexico City, 1942. (Box 22, Folder 13)
      Lists Walter Pach's article "Arte mexicano en Nueva York," no. 6, p. 5.
    - University Museum Bulletin (University Museum, University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia) 16, no. 3, 1952 February. (Box 22, Folder 14)
      Includes "Fourteen Eyes in a Museum Storeroom.".
    - Valentiner, William R. "The Museum of Tomorrow." In New Architecture and City Planning, edited by Paul Zucker. New York: Philosophical Library, Reprint, undated (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - Van Loon, Hendrik Willem. The Songs We Sing. New York: Simon and Schuster, Inc., 1936 (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - Variétés critiques. Paris: Les Editions G. Crès & Cie, undated (Box 22, Folder 17)
    - Venturi, Adolfo. Luca Signorelli. Firenze: Presso Giorgio & Piero Alinari, 1921-1922 (Box 22, Folder 18)
    - La Vie (Paris) no. 41, 1912 November 30 (Box 22, Folder 19)
    - La Vie (Paris) no. 42, 1912 December 7 (Box 22, Folder 20)
    - La Vie (Paris) no. 43, 1912 December 14 (Box 22, Folder 21)
    - La Vie des Lettres et des Arts (Paris), 1924 (Box 22, Folder 22)
      Includes "La peinture et ses lois: Ce qui devait sortir du cubisme," by Albert Gleizes.
    - View: Max Ernst Number (New York), 1942 (Box 22, Folder 23)
    - View, The Modern Magazine: Marcel Duchamp Number (New York) 5, no. 1, 1945 (Box 22, Folder 24)
    - Vollard, Ambroise. Le père Ubu à l'aviation. Paris: Editions Georges Crès et Cie, 1918 (Box 22, Folder 25)
    - Vollard, Ambroise. Le père Ubu à l'hôpital. Paris: Editions Georges Crès et Cie, 1918 (Box 22, Folder 26)
    - Vollard, Ambroise. Le père Ubu au pays des Soviets. Paris: Librairie Stock, Delamain, Boutelleau et Cie, 1930 (Box 22, Folder 27)
    - Vollard, Ambroise. Les réincarnations du père Ubu. Paris: Le Divan, 1925 (Box 22, Folder 28)
    - Walkowitz, Abraham. A Demonstration of Objective, Abstract, and Non-Objective Art. Girard, Kans.: Haldeman-Julius Publications, 1945 (Box 22, Folder 29)
    - Walkowitz, Abraham. Isadora Duncan in Her Dances. Girard, Kans.: Haldeman-Julius Publications, 1945 (Box 22, Folder 30)
    - Wechsler, Herman J., ed. The Pocket Book of Old Masters. New York: Pocket Books, Inc., 1949 (Box 22, Folder 31)
    - Wexley, John. The Last Mile. A play in three acts, with Preface by Lewis E. Lawes, Warden of Sing Sing Prison. New York and Los Angeles: Samuel French, 1930 (Box 22, Folder 32)
    - Whitney Museum of American Art. Abstract Painting in America. Introduction by Stuart Davis. New York, 1935 February 12-March 22 (Box 22, Folder 33)
    - Whitney Museum of American Art. Between Two Wars: Prints by American Artists, 1914-1941. New York, 1942 March 3-31. (Box 22, Folder 34)
      Walter Pach's work was in the exhibition.
    - Whitney Museum of American Art. The Decade of the Armory Show, 1910-1920. New York, 1963 (Box 22, Folder 35)